Official name

Jan Pavle Posma

Languages

Dutch (native), English (fluent; IELTS score 8.0 in 2010)

E-mail address j@npaulpos.ma Website

janpaulposma.nl

This is a shortened version. Find the full interactive document online at janpaulposma.nl/cv.

Curriculum Vitae: JP Posma

Experienced computer scientist & leader with a broad range of interests. Implementing impactful ideas. Fan of animal slippers and isochrones. I've written production code in **15 languages**, been paid to write code for **16 years**, and once used **25 wine glasses** in a project for MTV.

Professional experience

Cruise (staff software engineer)

2018 - 2020

At **Cruise** (self-driving car company) I was the tech lead on **Webviz**, an open source tool for visualizing what robots are "seeing" and "thinking". We pushed the browser to its limits with WebGL, manual memory management, WebAssembly (C++), streaming in gigabytes of data, etc. Webviz quickly became the **most used internal tool** within the company, and other companies and academic projects started using it as well. I also briefly worked on behaviour/manoeuvre planning (in the robotics group), and I was "bar raiser" for technical interviews.

Remix (tech lead + eng manager)

2016 - 2018

At **Remix** we built tools for designing public transportation, to help cities better serve their citizens. I mostly worked on the **scheduling product**, the company's second product. I ended up in a **tech lead and engineering manager dual-role**. I worked on every part of the product, including the data architecture, constraint satisfaction algorithms (e.g. integer linear programming), developer tools, user interfaces, external integrations, and so on.

2015 - 2016

Versal (senior software engineer)

2013 - 2015

Factlink (software engineer)

2012 – 2014

Wikimedia Foundation (software engineer)

2011 2009 – 2010

WorldTicketShop (software engineer)

Cantouch (multitouch engineering intern)

summer of 2009

Education

MSc in Computer Science, University of Oxford

2011 - 2012

My final project was **JavaScript dares**, an **interactive online programming course** aimed at high school students. It included an interactive **time-travel debugger**, which I later presented at conferences (e.g. Strange Loop).

BSc in Computing Science (cum laude), University of Groningen

2008 - 2011

For my bachelor thesis I researched new ways of **editing wikis** such as **Wikipedia**. In October 2010 I presented preliminary results at the MediaWiki Hack-A-Ton in Washington D.C. on invitation of the **Wikimedia Foundation**. In 2011 development continued in close collaboration with developers of **GRNET**, a Greek research institute. The final thesis received a mark of **9.5** (out of 10).

Willem Lodewijk Gymnasium, Groningen

2002 - 2008

My graduation project was **PimpMyBike**, an electronic circuit placed in the wheel of a bike, which displays an image when driving. I did everything from the circuit board design, component selection, and assembly, to the software (embedded+desktop).

Experience, prizes, and awards

Independent security research

2020

In my spare time I've been doing some security research: bug bounties as well as puzzles. I ranked #1 on the **HackerOne CTF** leaderboard for 2020.

Paper Programs 2018

Inspired by **Dynamicland**, a physical computing lab, I built **Paper Programs**, an open source programming environment where **physical pieces of paper** run computer programs. A camera detects and retrieves the program associated with each paper. I built this in two weeks, using React, OpenCV (C++ compiled to WebAssembly), Web Workers, and CSS transformation matrices.

For the **Generation Citizen Civic Tech Challenge 2015** a fellow programmer and I teamed up with a group that advocates for a lower voting age. In one day we put together a **website** that tells San Francisco voters why lowering the voting age is a good idea, and concrete steps they can take to help. Our team won the competition's **Civic Alignment Prize**.

λ Lessons (With Steve Krouse)

2014

In this hackathon hosted by Y Combinator we created λ Lessons, an open source Haskell course. For this we implemented a custom Haskell parser and interactive visualisation of functional expansion and reduction. Our work generated significant interest in the web development and functional programming community — even a spin-off was made, the very entertaining λ Bubble Pop.

Huygens Scholarship 2011

The Huygens Scholarship Programme awarded me a full scholarship to finance my studies in Oxford.

Science Center North (volunteer)

2008 - 2011

As an unpaid volunteer, I worked at **SCN** with children (age 10–18) on **electronics** and **programming** projects. I taught about soldering, (embedded) programming, and the drawing of schematics and circuit boards. We built **oscilloscope games**, **robots**, **aquarium discos**, and **alarm clocks** that played the Super Mario and Tetris themes.

National Informatics Olympiad

2007 - 2008

This competition is aimed at solving algorithmic problems and implementing them. In the national rounds I secured a **5th** and a **7th** place.

RoboChallenge Junior 2006 – 2007

With Marc van Beest

The aim of this national competition was to build a robot that is able to navigate on a grid and perform certain tasks. Our robot won the **1st place** in 2006, and the **3rd place** in 2007.

Various open source projects

I developed parts of **usbpicprog**, an open source, open hardware project, consisting of a **hardware device** and a piece of **cross-platform C++ software**.

I started OpenLaserFrag, an open source, open hardware laser-tag game, for which I built the hardware and embedded software.

For more information on my personal interests, please visit my website: janpaulposma.nl.